hello everyone how's it going Dr
incompetent here and let's play some
potion craft shall we I'd like to do a
complete beginner's guide to this game
to help brand new players or people who
are just starting out understand the
basics and fundamentals of alchemy and
making potions in this game now I have
just started this game a few weeks ago
myself and I've been playing lot and
also getting fantastic feedback and
commentary from YouTube viewers and so
what I'm going to do here is start up a
brand new game so you can play along
with me and I'm going to explain how to
play The Game's systems and give you
some tips and tricks to understand
exactly what it is you need to be doing
so that you can enjoy the game better
but in that process I'm going to draw on
my own Knowledge from trial and error
and probably more heavily on the
knowledge of people who have given me
tips and shown me things about the game
that I
overlooked the spirit of this guide is
not to be spoilery I'm not going to
reveal anything about what happens later
on as you go I'm not going to show you a
minmax optimized path that you need to
do to make the most money possible or
something like that but instead I'm just
going to explain the game so that you
can enjoy it and discover on your own
and just have a better footing because
the game is actually pretty deep and
complicated and yet if you know where to
look everything is right here to help
you explore that Alchemy map and start
making money and becoming a prosperous
new Alchemist so without further Ado
let's dive in and start a new game so as
you begin a new game it will give you
the option of taking a tutorial which
we'll do together so I can add on some
explanation and just show you everything
organically as it emerges I think this
guide will be helpful like I said to new
players and to um players who have been
playing for a little bit but have some
questions also though I want to make it
so that if you're considering buying the
game you know you might be able to get a
feel for what the game is like so I'm
going to recreate that brand new
experience and I'm not going to skip the
tutorial so I'm going to say
okay so you found an old abandoned house
on the edge of town judging by the
Alchemy equipment and garden the former
owner seems to have practiced Alchemy
apparently a wizard used to live here
but the layer of dust and condition of
the house suggest that it has been empty
for a long time all
right so we decide to turn the house
into a potion shop after several days of
cleaning and preparing the shop is ready
for its first customers it's time to
remember your Alchemy skill skills and
start this New Life in a new town so
right there is basically the story of
the game you find an abandoned house you
know some alchemy but seem to have
forgotten a lot of it and you want to
open up your own shop in this house you
clean it up and you start making it your
own and the game really isn't much about
story but more about the business of
exploring potions and potion making
however there is story that emerges and
you have the option of kind of talking
to customers and people who come into
your shop to get more lore or you can
just concentrate on playing the game if
you aren't interested in that now if you
want to see me read all of the lore and
go into that I do have a let's play so
you can watch me boot the game up for
the very first time and play through
further than the tutorial will go if you
want to see me cover uh some more
content that the game has to offer so
I'll link that in the description below
so get used to this screen because this
is what you're going to be looking at
and this game is going to strike you
immediately at least it did me because
it's not like many other games that you
play it is a very relaxed and chill
experience there is no time crunch that
you're necessarily on you aren't under
the gun Sweating Bullets you can go at
your own pace if you can of course set
goals for yourself and try to progress
faster through the content and I'm sure
you can speedrun and do all that jazz if
you want but that is not what I am doing
and what I really even recommend I
recommend just having fun listening to
this nice Medieval music taking in the
beautiful aesthetic of the game and
exploring and just honing your craft so
let's figure out how to do that so you
make potions from ingredients okay take
two Terraria and water Blooms from your
inventory and throw them in The Cauldron
to move ingredients click and hold the
mouse drag them to the cauldron and let
go pay attention to the Alchemy map on
the laboratory wall it shows you the
path the ingredients create once they
are added to the cauldron
so um what I want to do is just talk to
you about what you see on the screen and
add to what the tutorial presents you
with number one this scroll that rolls
down kind of like a projector screen in
a classroom is your Alchemy map so this
right here on the wall with the blue
potion in the center is your Alchemy map
and it is clouded over because you
haven't explored it and as you move this
potion bottle in different directions
the fog of War on the map will uncover
and you will find New Paths to
potions over here on the right of the
screen you will see um a panel that has
uh an amazing amount of good information
lots of it is grayed out and gated
because we're in a tutorial but I'll
just walk you through uh what you see so
here on this calendar is the day here's
how much gold we have in the upper
middle this is our popularity level
which is basically like how many people
just know about us overall
this is our reputation which is whether
or not we have reputation for being a
good alchemist that heals people or a
more uh unscrupulous kind
of Alchemist who makes poisons and
things for people and
curses over here this is our level and
experience gauge all right and we'll
talk more about some of this stuff as it
comes up but I just want to show you a
general sense of what you have and what
we want to focus on right now is that we
have four tabs on this main
screen more will be added um potentially
to this but right now we have an all tab
we have an ingredients tab which is kind
of like this leaf and berries and
Crystal we have a potions tab where our
finished potions will go and then we
have a miscellaneous tab so right now I
can either just click on my ingredients
tab or just leave it on the all tab
because all I have are this Terraria and
this water Bloom
now when I Mouse over the Terraria
notice that the tool tip emerges and it
shows you the path that the potion will
take both on the tool tip and then if
you look over into the center of the
screen at the Alchemy map it shows you
the path that this will take if you put
it into the cauldron now in fact it's
actually showing
you um that right now the dotted line
with the x is how far and what direction
the potion will
go if I just drop it into the cauldron
The Cauldron is you know the big
cauldron that you see at the bottom
center of the screen with the emblem on
it and if I just drop it in there I'll
move it and it will follow that dotted
line that path exactly and go to where
the x is now you can see that there are
some Whited out dashes that move further
down and terminate in a mortar and
pestal con that is how far I could move
the potion if I were to grind up the
Terraria in a mortar and pestal and then
put it into my cauldron now I don't
have a mortar and pestal right now
because I'm in the tutorial but I'll get
it very soon now I'll show you exactly
as they say you just hover the hand over
the Terraria you left click on it and
when you pick it up you see how it
transforms into this like ball of the
ingredients okay and you'll notice that
the um number that I have went from from
two down to one because I've got it in
my hand now if I let it go over the
Terraria on my list over here I can put
this back and just put it back to two
Okay um now if I pick it up I need to
drop this in my cauldron so basically I
just kind of I'm holding the left Mouse
button and I just drop it into the
cauldron I could drop it from way up
high I could drop it from down low okay
if I drop it off to the side you'll see
how it like breaks up do not worry it is
not lost you can just left click you
gather it up and just pick it up now I'm
going to just show you yeah you can drop
it in from way up high it splashes and
that's no problem okay now that I've
committed that to the potion all right
you'll see that the path that the potion
is going to go is locked in and it is
terminating in this x now if I Mouse
over another piece of Terraria you'll
see
that it's going to go even further and
there is the completely chocked in path
that I'm going because of what I've
committed to my cauldron you cannot
remove anything from your cauldron once
you put it in there okay um so you can't
get ingredients back out of there if you
drop them on the floor or anything like
that you can pick them up and put them
back over on your ingredient tab but
once you put them in The Cauldron it's
done
now um if I drop this in there is a
darker line that goes underneath that
shows where I I will go next and so I'll
just do that and I dropped it in from a
little bit shallower that time and you
can see that yep indeed we've added on
to the root and if I now go to the water
Bloom okay and put this in I'll drop it
in from like really really low almost
over top of the cauldron just showing
you how generous the game is remember
this is not a game that's trying to
punish you this is a game to enjoy to
Sav her over if you want to chill out VI
out be an alchemist do that it's not
like you need to have incredible
Precision at this point you will need
some more Precision later but it's still
very casual and I'll explain it
now this is now the path that we've
created we go we're going down in this
windy route and then we're going over to
the right in an kind of undulating sinu
soidal fashion and I'll just drop that
down like that now the ladle has
appeared because the game wants us to
stir so once we stir the potion which is
always starts right here on our Alchemy
map at least right now um we start to
follow this path now you see how I just
kind of moved in and out you can zoom in
and out on the Alchemy map with the
mouse wheel just to get a feel for like
how ginormous this whole thing is okay
and you see this little book icon here
on the path this is an experienced node
and so anything that you touch that's a
book like this with your potion as it's
pathing around you will get this book
and it will give you experience to help
you level up now if I want to move this
here I need to stir the potion it tells
you how to do this here I am not going
to probably read all of this um in its
entirety I'll just explain it to you as
I feel necessary but in my let's play I
do read through all of this stuff if
you're interested you can always just
pause the video read through it on your
own or do it when you play the game now
it does tell you in fact that all you
need to do is click on the spoon okay
and you see how it has a circular
pattern you can just make it like you
can put your hand in the shape of a
circle if you want or you can just go
back left and right you can let go of
the spoon at anytime to stop the potion
and did you see how when I did hit the
book I got a plus 20 experience
you'll notice right here it tells you
accumulating experience lets you level
up but has no effect on the current
potion so it doesn't change our potion
it just gives us experience the outer
wheel of our experience Circle has
filled up and as I continue stirring and
you can do this like really minutely if
you want you don't have to be crazy I
just kind of go right to left you'll see
that we're pathing and you can go as
fast or as slow as you want all right
and We've Ended up here
now I want you to notice several things
number one on the Alchemy map okay you
see how radiating out from this Center
potion which is where you start with
water-based potions water-based potions
um is what you begin the game with it's
all you can do and so your potion will
start here when you're starting with
water as your base and these dotted
lines that go out from this are
indicating that there is a potion that
you can learn if you go in this
direction so you can see right here how
this potion is connected to this
starting point with a dotted line and I
couldn't see it before because the
Alchemy map was blocked over but if I
move in that way I start to clear out
space okay and I can see more and more
now I can zoom out to kind of get a
bigger picture or I can zoom in uh to
get a feel for where I'm at and this
will become much more important later
now once I move my potion bottle over
the potion that has a question mark that
I'm hovering over
here I don't know what potion I'll make
here but this indicates that this can be
a potion all I have to do is touch my
potion bottle to this potion that's
drawn on the Alchemy map the closer I
get my bottle to overlapping the potion
bottle that's on the map the more potent
my potion will become the stronger it
will be the more money people will pay
for it that is indicated by this Roman
numeral here right now it's a Roman
numeral one meaning this is the weakest
kind of potion that I can make that is
at this location because I'm not very
lined up you can see how I barely
overlap it all right now if you want to
see what kind of potion this is you need
to heat it up so there's these coals
under your potion and they've just added
the Bellows to our screen all you need
to do is just hover over this anything
in the game that you can interact with
on your Alchemy screen when you hover
over it with the hand it'll change from
a pointer to like a gripping motion and
you'll see kind of a a a uh stroke
around what you can interact with with a
transparency to indicate that yep that's
what I can do I can grab the Bellow so I
hold left click and then I just pull
this
down I don't need to do this quickly but
I can if I want I can do it nice and
slowly and once I've given that fire
enough
energy it'll heat up and boom we have
made a potion of
healing once we do this okay the potion
transforms it gets a new color and it
tells us that we've made a weak potion
of healing the left panel of our Alchemy
map screen has been exposed on the top
of this panel there's a zoom function
you can see as I zoom in and out with
the wheel this slider shows
the rate of my zoom I can even just grab
this and drag it left and right or I can
click on the plus and minus or use the
mouse wheel to zoom in and out and it
says we finished a potion so you've
added a new effect to the potion um
which is healing to finish it we just
click this green button that says finish
potion now let me walk you through what
you see
here okay so there's a lot to this but
it's very simple once you understand it
but not everything is explained which is
partially why I wanted to make this
tutorial so look at this it tells you
what your potion is the weak potion of
healing and you see here that it has a
healing effect there are five Pips you
can see one is taken up by this heart
which is healing a potion can have up to
five different effects okay so you could
have five different effects at the
weakest level but if you have a potion
that is more
potent then more Hearts will appear here
so if it's a level two potion then two
hearts would appear here taking up two
of the five possible effects that I can
have here and a level three potion would
take up three of the five so this is a
good way to keep track of what's in your
potion and at what magnitude it exists
right here this shows you what you did
to get this potion you started with the
water base you added two Terraria and
two water Bloom so it keeps track of the
ingredients in your base this is
cosmetic stuff where you can change the
shape of your bottle you can change how
the label looks you can change the name
of it and stuff like that but for right
now all we can do is finish the potion
and so I did it and I finished the
potion now you can see on our all tab on
the right panel we have some ingredients
we have a Terraria that they've given us
and we also have a finished potion a
weak potion of healing okay and if I go
to potion tab you'll see here's my weak
potion of healing if I go to my
ingredients tab they show me Terraria
and they've given me Terraria because
they want me to now use the mortar and
pestal okay so now we've got ourselves
yet another tool in our Alchemy Workshop
which is the mortar and pestle and it
goes down here to the right of our
cauldron now what you want to do with
the mortar and pestl is as you would
expect GR wind up ingredients but let me
explain the process so if I take my
Terraria let me zoom out on the map so
you can see the full path you notice how
if I'm zoomed in like I was you kind of
couldn't quite see exactly where you
would go but you can zoom out um and you
have to actually be hovering over the
Alchemy map by the way with the mouse
wheel to zoom in and out like that
now with the
Terraria again if we just drop it into
cauldron we'll get to where the first
first X goes but if we drop this in the
mortar and pestal and grind it fully
we'll get all the way down to where the
mortar and pestal icon is on our Alchemy
map let me show you this again all you
have to do is just drag it over and
instead of dropping it in your cauldron
you drop it in your mortar and pestl
remember to drop it in the right place
cuz once it's in your cauldron you can't
get it back out now again if you miss
you can always just pick it up and put
it in here and you'll notice that when
you do this and you're picking stuff up
the exterior of your mortar and pestal
um becomes transparent so you can see
into it and you just drop it in there
now once it's in here what you have to
do is you take your hand and you Mouse
over um the pestl
okay and you just pick this part up and
you can open it up and just smash this
down in here now watch on the path in
the Alchemy map as I grind it a little
bit you'll notice that the X moves along
the dotted path to reflect how much I
have ground this ingredient so this is
important to note because sometimes you
don't want to go all the way and you
only want to go a part of the way on
your path um but in this case we're
going to grind it fully so you just keep
smashing it and it might look like it's
done but you'll notice on the path it is
not so you just grind it until you're SA
satisfied with the the um path that you
get to or until it won't go anymore
whatever you're looking for and then you
let go and you just go ahead and grab
this right
here and you drop it in your
cauldron all right so now the game has
given us some water Bloom and you'll
notice
that this is going to take us off to the
right and if we completely grind it
we're going to get all the way to our
healing potion because we have uncovered
this potion you see the heart here
you'll notice that it's it's clear to us
like this is a healing potion it's not a
question mark we've uncovered it because
we fired a potion there now if I go
ahead and do
this and I grind this all the way
up now I can just pick this ground ball
up and drop it into the cauldron and
we need to just stir the cauldron and
we'll get this all the way over by the
way I just leveled up you see the green
ticket come down level up plus one
Talent point because we hit a book on
the way and I'm going to just keep
stirring okay stirring until we get to
the healing potion and then all we need
to do is just heat this up with the
Billows and
boom we've made a new potion but what's
important about that is you notice that
grinding up your herbs increases the
potency it doubles it all right so what
happened is we were now able to make the
weak potion of healing just like before
but using half the ingredients by
grinding it up now what the game is
telling you is a fantastic feature which
is saving a potion recipe so you have a
magical recipe book and in it you can
save the potion recipe and what this
allows you to do is later on
if you simply want to make this potion
and you don't want to go through the
process of grinding the ingredients and
moving things around you can click on
your recipe and just make it from there
instantly providing you have the
ingredients okay um so what we're going
to do is we're going to click this
button right here um and it says save
recipe and it goes into our recipe book
you can see it fly over here and this
little green book with the potion on it
that is our recipe book
um we can't use it in the tutorial and
then now that we're done we'll finish it
and we have another potion and these are
both the same potion but they don't go
in the same stack simply because they
were made using different ingredient
quantities all right um moving between
rooms you are the owner of a potion shop
and your task is not only to brew
potions but also sell them so what
they're telling you is it's kind of like
um hard to see but there are the these
arrows all over the sides of this room
telling us we can go up we can go right
we can go down and we can go to um the
left and from our Alchemy chamber
here if we go to the left we get to the
shop part of our
establishment and I'm just going to you
can either click on this or push a and
you move over to the shop and what
happens is people are going to come in
and ask for a
potion all right and they're telling you
that basically if they like the potion
they will have a positive reaction with
these lines coming out and they'll pay
more for it and if they hate the potion
um they will have an angry face so this
gives you an idea of what it's going to
be like to sell to customers um but
let's just look at the process directly
so we say okay and here comes our first
customer and it says offer a potion for
sale and put it on this scale so you
always put what you're giving them on
the right and over here they'll put
their payment now she's going to come in
or whoever comes in and they describe
what they need and your job is to take
their description and use it to best
estimate what potion you could give them
to solve their problem so she says her
husband has been ill for some time now
but recently he got even worse now he
can't even get up he has a fever and
sweats do you have any medicine for my
poor husband and generally if anybody
has any kind of pain or needs to recover
you always just give them a healing
potion and so you just grab it from your
inventory and you can use either one and
then you just drop it like we're used to
onto the scale um and I dropped it from
too high and it like fell through but
you can just drop it um and then you see
all the the bars like Illuminating when
you're in the right place and you see
her reaction all right you can see it
again if you want and um she had a
positive
reaction and she says I'll buy this
potion but I won't pay very much okay
and the reason she won't pay very much
is because this is only a level one a
healing one potion If This Were healing
three which is the best we can make
right now um then she would be even
happier and would pay us more money now
we can't haggle right now um we can just
sell it in this green bar for 10 gold
and we're going to do that just like
this now we got 10 gold two reputation
and two popularity that's what all those
things meant so you could see right here
we got two popularity and we got two
positive reputation and we got 10 gold
okay so that was tremendous now this guy
says um I was just walking down the
street minding my own business when a
flower pot fell out of nowhere and
bonked him on the head so he got hit in
the head and he wants a potion so what
we're going to do is offer him the only
other potion we have which is healing
and now they're going to introduced the
haggling mechanic so whenever you sell
something to people you have the option
to sell it and you have the option to
haggle okay now um something I want to
tell you about haggling and this took me
a second because it it shows you in the
game but it's not quite as obvious
you'll notice here there's this grade
out minus one star and what this means
is
basically every time you haggle with
customers you get one less popularity
Point than when you uh sell it straight
out okay so we're going to just haggle
and this is the haggling screen now you
can go for an easy topic a medium topic
or a very easy topic now I'm going to
recommend just start with very easy so
you can get used to this miname all it
does as you increase the difficulty
level of the haggling um is make it
faster but you get more payout if you
haggle at a higher um speed or more
difficult topic so so for example with
very easy talking about the weather I
get more two more gold than I normally
would but if I go for food um I would
get plus four Gold All right so this is
all you need to do now to haggle your
arrow starts here on this green box now
you pretty much in the beginning I never
try to click on the again when my arrow
is in the handshake box because that
will end the deal right there what you
want to do is when you click Start
haggling this needle or this Arrow will
move back and forth in this box and you
just need to click th this button right
here the haggle button when it is
pointing at one of these Yellow Boxes
okay and every time you do that this the
negotiation will tip in your favor now
you can go back if you don't want a
haggle okay or you can just push
question mark to get information about
haggling and it opens up this whole like
screen um here
that explains haggling in Greater detail
okay and when you're done with this you
just click in the upper right on this
Wax Seal with the go back button so I'm
going to click on start haggling and
watch the needle click I missed click
click okay and click click click so when
you miss it doesn't end the
deal but
successful attempts will trigger the
scales in your favor and if you miss a
lot or a lot of time passes it will tick
over and the downside is basically they
will still buy the potion from you if
you fail the negotiation with the haggle
attempt but they will pay you less money
for it so I always try to haggle and do
it successfully unless I really really
want popularity points you know what I
mean like um but it's not a huge deal
right now but if I'm about to level up
maybe I want it now um you can see
instead of getting 10 we're going to get
plus two it's indicated right here and
we can now just click sell and we get
one popularity two reputation and 12
money lack of suitable potions is what
happens when you don't have the potion
that they need but this is where the
game gets really cool okay it says right
here there is no time limit so you can
focus on the recipe the client will not
leave this is when I really Ood the game
and felt great about it which is that
it's you're not under the gun she wants
you to make a potion that gets rid of
mice that have infested her Hut so we
need a
potion that we don't have yet but it's
not a healing potion so all you have to
do is go make a potion to do that and
she'll never leave so you are under no
time crunch okay now they're telling us
they want us to go to the Enchanted
Garden which is two screens to the right
from here so you just push D or click on
this this is our Alchemy Shop and if you
click over here you go to the garden now
the garden is where you can gather
ingredients okay like I have this
firebell here and I have this Terraria
here now something I want you to tell
you is uh there's two things number one
you can gather every day from your
garden but number two when you're
clicking on the items in your garden you
can only gather them once but you don't
just get one so if I click on this fire
Bell you see how it said plus one and if
I I click on this it says plus one in
this case I did just get one but when
you're actually playing the game not in
the tutorial you can get more than one
from a picture so don't think it's just
one of each like I thought that but then
actually I might get five like when I
click on that instead of just one so
just understand that you might be
getting more than just what it looks
like graphically you'll see an
indication pop up that tells you exactly
how many
um pieces of Terraria you gathered for
example now they only give us the exact
amount we need to make a specific potion
so we're going to go back to the
laboratory and do that okay so now they
want us to brew a bottle of poisoning to
take care of her ramp problem and
they're opening up the game a little bit
and they're saying try making a potion
yourself so we get to do this without
too much direct guidance don't forget to
use all the Alchemy equipment available
don't be afraid of failure you can
always try again by pressing the button
below so they give you this try again
again button to reset to this game state
if you make a mistake so you can just do
whatever you like all right so here's
what I'm going to do I'm going to kind
of zoom out and show you that a bottle
of poisoning okay well where is it where
could it be we don't know on the Alchemy
map exactly where this potion is but we
have some
Clues number one always look at these
faint dotted lines to indicate where a
potion might be residing and we already
have this one but also look at the
potions that we've been given and what
directions they will go on the Alchemy
map okay so this is going to go down and
this is going to go to the left
so at best I can kind of go over to the
left and down so if I use both of these
I'm going to kind of end up in this
general direction I'll go to the left
and then I'll go down probably following
this diagonal line in this way and
because I already have down mapped out
let's go ahead and go to the left first
now something that is wasn't explained
but I got in the comments uh from one of
my earlier videos in the let's play that
was so awesome and helpful to me was you
see right here there's this Elemental
compass on the right panel and if you
click on a
direction like if I click on going left
this is the fire element West left
whatever way you want to say with this
and it will sort your ingredients based
on which one will take you in that
direction the best and then in this sub
panel you can choose do you want to go
short distance do you want to go long
distance do you want to organize your
ingredients by type or by how much they
cost or how many you have of them or
just alphabetically okay but I usually
like to organize ize them by whichever
will go the longest distance in the
direction that I want now you can just
do whatever uh you like but this is
incredibly powerful so for example if I
click earth going down you'll see that
it takes Terraria and it puts that first
because that's a better potion for going
down so you can use this to help um sort
your ingredients so that when you want
to move in a particular way on your
Alchemy map you can do this more
efficiently than just mousing over every
single ingredient which is what I used
to do and right now I only have two but
very soon you're going to have a bunch
so let's go to the left and again we're
going to want to grind this up to take
it as far left as we can go and uncover
some of the map so I'm just going to
drop this firebell okay down in here and
you can see that we will go to where the
mortar and pestal icon is to the left so
just grind grind grind all the
way and once I'm done what I'm actually
going to do at this point is just drop
it into my cauldron and I'm not ready
yet but I'm just going to stir and kind
of see what becomes uncovered before I
even add this all right because if I see
something uncover and I want to go down
immediately you know um or I I might
want to just make a a change on my game
plan I can do
that but I will tell you this you can't
change um let me kind of edit that you
can change your game plan based on once
you reached your destination of where
you stir but you see where the x is even
if I were to add in Terraria to my
cauldron I still have to finish out what
I've added to the cauldron I can't stop
it once I've put that in there that's
why sometimes you only want to grind a
little bit um because it will set how
far you go you go to the max of where
you've set the path once it's in the
cauldron and you cannot alter that the
only thing you can do is just stop
stirring and hit the Bellows and fire
right
there um all right at least right now in
the game okay so I'm going to do that
and that's as far as I can go to the
left we got some books okay I'm going to
drop this down in here and I'm just
going to blast this up and once I get
this completely ground you see how we're
going to go down here and it's going to
be right along this dotted path I'm
going to drop this in and we'll get a
book and then look we found a potion
here now we're not really lined up
perfectly but we don't have any other
ingredients so this is as good as we can
do and we're just going to fire this up
and we have discovered poisoning so we
found a new effect you can see the
bottle looks different it's green with
this Sinister Blade with a dripping
poison uh dot coming down here and if I
like this okay I can just save the
recipe and right now I can just save
recipes but you you are limited with how
many recipes you can save based on how
many Magic Pages you have in your recipe
book now right now you start with 12
each potion takes up one but you can
freely delete or erase Pages if you
don't want a potion anymore so I say
just go ahead and memorize as many
potions as you can just so you have them
to consult even if you're not going to
use them to instantly deliver on the
potion now I'm going to finish the
potion and we're going to return to the
shop by pushing a on the keyboard to
move to the left and she's here she
still wants her rat potion and she's not
upset it doesn't affect the price on how
fast you go or anything like that so we
dropped this here um now this is 13 it's
going to sell for 13 we could haggle to
get more money but you can do whatever
you want okay my recommendation you see
how we
need um eight popularity to get get to
the next popularity level okay it tells
you when you Mouse over at what
popularity and reputation do for you and
popularity means if we increase this um
we'll get more money when we haggle uh
and it'll generally just alert more
people to your store so you'll have um
you know more people coming into your
shop uh and so I want popularity more
than I want the extra two gold or
whatever I would get by haggling given
my low level so I'm just going to sell
this right out but if you want to
practice the haggle mini game and sell
this for one less popularity you can do
that but I'm going to sell it to her
right now see two popularity two rep 13
gold I'm just trying to get the word out
about our store so I'm kind of like
taking a little bit of a loss on profits
because I want I value these more now
the other thing is reputation um if you
were selling that poison to somebody who
said like I want to kill somebody with
this um then you will lose like
reputation it'll go down like because
you're kind of an unsavory Alchemist
selling poison for murder but that did
not hurt our reputation because um rat
poison is like okay people are fine with
killing pests or something like that but
you just have to kind of be careful now
if you want to play that way if you want
to be like the you know no um like gray
morality or just outright evil Alchemist
that's on you you can do whatever you
like I'm just playing it as a good
Alchemist and just want to let you know
of the reputation interaction there and
then now that the customer is done um
they want us to go to sleep uh because
we've ended the day so we go over back
to our laboratory and then if we go up
we go into our
bedroom and to end the day you just
click on the bed you can see the
calendar above our head it's day one and
if we click on this and it says are you
sure you want to go to bed you say yes
and then you'll see this move Moon
Passover head and you get to day two all
right and this is the end of the
tutorial excellent you have refreshed
your Alchemy knowledge and familiarized
yourself with the Alchemy equipment in
the Attic next to the bed you found a
few ingredients and a ladle for water
okay so now we got a ladle um which I'll
talk to you about in a moment and now
the game just opens up and lets you do
whatever you want um I mean as long as
what you want is selling potions and you
say okay and they've given us lots of
ingredients you can see we have a bunch
of more ingredients here the first thing
you want to do every morning is go down
go to the right and go into your garden
and you get a goal achieved there's all
these goals that you can accomplish
especially early on just kind of like
give you um a way to progress in the
game by giving you experience and just
help you have things to do targets and
goals to shoot for so um right now just
click on every single thing in your
garden and just click away you can't
miss you can't do anything wrong all you
can do is Miss something but you can
come back and get it but if you rest if
you don't gather stuff and you rest um
for the next day then uh you will uh
lose that those things at least I think
so I've never not done that but that's
my guess now you'll notice that here's
our book The Alchemist path and it has
this badge with a two on it I'm going to
click on
this and it's separated into chapters
and it gives you a whole bunch of like
short-term goals to achieve it tells you
how much experience you'll get for doing
it and it gives you a bonus for
completing the chapter of a substantial
amount of experience so I just set to
doing these as just giving myself things
to do within the game of course the main
thing you want to do is just you know
try to make money and be successful uh
explore and have fun but this is great
for helping you do that okay now the
green book is our recipe book you can
switch here and change between the tabs
that you have um you can click on this x
to delete it you can continue Brewing
from here if you want to give a potion
an effect and then start there but then
you want to keep going to add another
effect from this location if you click
this or this Brew or continue Brewing
you will use the ingredients that you
have listed uh so just be aware of that
and you can see the recipe is really
detailed it tells you like how many
times I stirred it how many times I used
the Bellows and everything uh so you can
do these and make them more efficiently
uh as you like and just erase them once
you're don't want that recipe anymore
going to close this up there is the help
manual here which is very useful okay
there's legendary recipes there's shop
upgrades and there are the main menu
settings this tells us the day that
we're
at this is all all of our stuff our
ingredients our potions and our
miscellaneous and here here's leveling
up let's talk about this so you if you
have a pulsing plus sign on your level
up symbol in the upper right that means
that you have talent points to
distribute so we're level three so I
click on this and I have um two Talent
points to distribute down these four
paths and this path gives you more
radius discovered when you're exploring
the Alchemy map so like when you're
moving to potion around the fog of War
will uncover at a greater rate if you
take
this this gives you a chance to spawn
bonus experience books on the Alchemy
map that are Green books that appear
each day as opposed to the Brown books
which are permanently there until you
discover
them then there's the trading which
gives you more money and there's
haggling but it's quite expensive I
recommend when you're starting out to do
all of these things really I mean
they're all good but I kind of like
making more money and getting more
experience visibility is fine um but I
haven't noticed it to be as important as
these two and yet I kind of just equally
distribute this down with an emphasis on
making money all right so I'm going to
put two points right here and you see we
got a goal achieved for doing that okay
close this up and then we go over to our
lab and the only thing I want to show
you is the ladle okay so you can use
this Ladle pick it up and pour water in
and what this will do is dilute your
potion so it will draw your potion on
the line back to the center point so you
can use this very strategically to
better line up your potion with one of
these established or yet to be
discovered potion symbols to get higher
potency potions and line things up there
will always be a little line that
appears from your potion wherever it is
exploring that will show you where you
will go when you use the ladle and you
can do this really really slowly and and
as minimally as you want to just get
that extra nudge so using the ladle to
move it back and then using the
different Paths of the ingredients will
be how you explore and line things up so
everyone I think this is a good place to
end this beginner guide first episode
I'm going to play more and uncover some
more things for you and help give you
some more best practices but for now
we've done the tutorial and you know I
really think this is a great Foundation
to understanding everything that the
game has to offer at this point and lets
you explore and have fun on your own if
you have any questions um I'd love to
answer those for you in the comments
below if I got anything wrong please
correct me so that new players will have
um all of the most accurate information
but remember keep it non-spoilery please
try to preserve people's um mystery and
sense of Discovery with the game by not
spoiling anything uh too heavily and
also the final thing I want to say is
prioritize buying as many ingredients as
you can whenever you get the opportunity
for it um providing their um on sale
because these uh are your lifeblood and
you really can't do much if you can't
make potions so try to get ingredients
when the opportunity presents itself um
all right everyone thank you so much for
watching take care